This is the grave I've chosen for Shilang
これは私が石狼のために選んだ墓です
This place is called Tiannan Pass
ここは天南関と呼ばれています
Composed of two peaks, east and west
東西二つの山峰で構成されている
Adjacent to Tianhe
天河に隣接する
Only one narrow path in between for troops to pass
中央には行軍が通れる小道が一本だけあります
If a large army marches here
大軍がもしここまで進軍すれば
They will inevitably form a long line
必然的に長い列を作る
Front and rear cannot support each other
始めと終わりを同時に面倒を見るのは難しい
We only need
私たちはただするだけです
To lure the enemy here
敵を誘い込んでここまで来させる
The vanguard
元軍による
Will block Shilang
石の狼を封じる
The rear guard will take the mountain paths
後方の軍隊は谷間の小道を進む
In groups to encircle from behind
分けて後方から回り込む
If we encounter enemy troops
もし敵軍に遭遇したら
Don't engage
絡まないで
Just disperse them
散らすだけでいい
And I
そして私
Will set the central camp on the mountain
中軍の本営を山の上に設置するだろう
After Shilang's main force is attacked
石狼の主力が襲撃に遭った後
They will surely flee along the mountain paths
きっと谷間の小道から逃げ散るだろう
At that time
その時
I will personally lead the central army to intercept the fleeing enemy
私は自ら中軍を率いて敵の逃亡兵を迎え撃つだろう
This battle
この戦い
Must completely annihilate their 50,000 main force
彼らの五万の主力軍を必ず守らなければならない
Completely
すべて全滅した
In this way
こういうふうにして
Shi Wei's so-called 180,000 army
石魏のいわゆる十八万の大軍
Will scatter like birds and beasts
やがて鳥獣のように散り散りになるだろう
The Central Plains can be pacified
中原 可定
The task of luring the enemy is very dangerous
敵を誘き寄せる任務は非常に危険です
Who is willing to be the vanguard?
誰が先駆者になりたいか
Father
父上
You can't catch a wolf without risking the child
子供を手放せないなら狼は捕えられない
Your son is willing to be the vanguard
私は先鋒として仕えたい
Good
はい
I'll give you a unit of elite cavalry
私はあなたに一隊の精鋭騎兵を与えます
To lure Shilang's main force into the pass
引石狼の主力が関中に入る
Yes
はい
Halt
止まれ
Who goes there?
誰
They say Wuzhao people are brave and skilled
人々は皆邬伖の人々が勇敢で戦いに秀でていると言う
How
どう
How come all I see today are cowards?
どうして今日私が会ったおじいちゃんはみんな臆病者ばかりなんだろう
Everyone inside, listen
中にいる人みんな聞いてください
Who dares come out and fight me?
誰が出てきてじいさんと戦う勇気があるのか
Young General
少将
General Shilang said
石狼将軍が言いました
No one is to go out and fight
誰も城を出て戦いに行くことはできないよ
To hell with that
くそったれ
I'll kill this brat first
この小さなウサギを先に屠殺します
Young General
少将
Report
報
Shilang's army is moving
石狼の大軍が動き出した
Good, the Second Prince is brave
いいね第二皇子は威風堂々だね
If Shilang wants to maintain morale
彼石狼は士気を保とうとしたい場合
He will surely follow
必ず追随することになる
Zu Yue
ソゲツ
Lead your troops
あなたは自分の部隊を率いる
To face the Second Prince head-on
正面から次男に立ち向かう
Fight while retreating
戦いながら撤退する
Your servant
しん
Receives the order
承知しました
Zhu Yuanzhi
朱元之
Half an hour after Shilang's main force enters the pass
待石狼の主力が関を入った後半時間
Lead the ambush troops to attack
あなたは伏兵を率いて攻撃する
Block Shilang's army's retreat
石狼の大軍の後方ルートを塞ぐ
Your servant receives the order
臣命を承る
Brat, give me back my son's life
ガキ俺の息子の命を返せ
Bad, there's an ambush
まずい待ち伏せがある
Kill
殺す
Kill them
死にそうです
Report
報
Shilang's army has all entered the pass
石狼の大軍はすでにすべての峠道に入った
Shilang discovered he's surrounded
石の狼が囲まれていることに気づいた
Instead of retreating, he advances
退くどころか前進する
Sending heavy armor to break through
重装甲部隊を配置して陣を組む
One charge has broken through two lines
一回の突撃が二重の封鎖線を突破した
They know they're ambushed
彼らはわざと罠にかかったことを知っている
Yet still lead the army deeper
しかしまだ軍を深く進める
Report
報
Minister Li Dingyuan
李定遠さま李大人
Sent an urgent message from the rear
急信を後方に速馬で送る
Your Majesty
陛下
Some are planning rebellion
変化を望む人がいる
Minister Li says
李さんは言いました
Many gentry believe this battle is hopeless
多くの士族はこの戦いに希望を見いだせないと感じている
And are stirring panic in the rear
後方で恐怖を煽る
The Chen and Xie families
陳家と謝家
Will handle it
うまく処理できます
Your Majesty
陛下
But the Chen family head
チェン家の家長
Is now the Second Prince's mother
今は二皇子の母后です